outtravel.it 2011-06-04

# Privacy - Out Travel

Privacy policy, as per Italian D.lgs 30.06.2003 N.196, Art. 13

This privacy policy, as per Italian D.lgs 30.06.2003 N.196, Art. 13 regulating in Italy all European Union directives on the matter, sets out how Out Travel S.r.L. uses and protects any information that you give Out Travel S.r.L. when you use this website.

Out Travel S.r.L. is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

Out Travel S.r.L. may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page every time you visit this website to ensure that you are happy with any changes.

  1. **Handling of the data**  
The handling of the personal data is carried out to ensuring that your information is secure and private, and is carried out with manual and electronic means to memorize, handle and forward the data. Personal data will be handled following proper standards, collected and registered for specific purposes, explicit and legitimate, exact and, if necessary, appropriate, complete and not exceeding the standards requested to fulfill the obligation, stored in a way that will allow to recognize the individual only for a period of time not exceeding the time required to fulfill the obligation for which they have originally been collected and subsequently handled. 
  2. **Data provided voluntarily by users**  
Out Travel S.r.L. collects personal information and other data, which are submitted by users voluntarily via web or mobile registration forms, as well as forwarded to the Company via mail or email in an explicit and voluntary way. Such data may concern essential information required to carry out the service requested by the user (i.e. Newsletter) and/or to contact the user (name, mail address, any other personal data inserted in the letter).

The optional, explicit and voluntary forwarding of emails to the address given on this site, implies the acquisition of the email address, essential to reply to the requests, and of any other additional personal data in the communication. Surfing data collected by electronic means Information systems and software procedures for the correct functioning of the Out Travel S.r.L. web and mobile sites acquire, during normal use, personal data, whose transmission is implicit in the use of internet communication protocols (i.e. user IP address or domain name of the computer used to access the web, URI of the requested resources, time of request or session time, server submitted query method used, files’ size received as request response, numeric code concerning the status of the server response and other kind of information related to the operating system and the user IT environment). The Out Travel S.r.L. website uses technologies like cookies, to collect statistical information on the use of the web (i.e. total number of visitors on the sites, number of visitors per single page, name of the domain of origin of visitors’ internet services supplier) and to improve the surfing experience.

  3. **Cookies**  
During surfing of the Out Travel S.r.L. website, information is collected through files called "cookies", which help to identify your computer or browser. A cookie is an encrypted string of text stored on your computer or on the mobile phone, to be able to recognise it quickly the next time. In the case of Mobilesite cookies, the latter memorise only name, surname and ticket number. In the case of computer cookies, these allow a customisation of an internet website, to make surfing smoother and an improved display of most requested information by quantitative check-out of web pages access. Cookies used do not memorise personal data except the IP address. Cookies retained information is anonymous and remain so as the cookie identification number is not associated to personal data supplied by surfers. 

You may always disenable cookies by changing your browser settings. 

  4. **Why we collect data**  
Out Travel collects the necessary personal data of the users to carry out authorization, habilitation and personalization of accesses to the various areas and contents of the Company’s website. Furthermore, Out Travel S.r.L. collects the necessary data to fulfill its contractual obligations towards clients, deriving from booking processes and purchases of travel means. We require this information to provide you with this service, giving access to the data to operational and commercial Out Travel staff as well as third party companies providing a service.  
The personal and/or sensitive data given or acquired during the contractual relationship may be given, in the measure requested to carry out the service, to: 
    1. Internal Out Travel S.r.L.personnel with the intent of improving our products and services (as per D.Lgs 196/2003
    2. Third party companies carrying out services which are essential towards Out Travel operations.
With reference to sensitive data, these may be handled even without explicit consent of the person as per art. 26, n.4, D. Lgs 196/2003. However these data will not be distributed. Be reminded that from time to time (not as part of the ordinary management of this website) the Authorities may request information and details as per art. 157 of D. Lgs. 196/2003, to check on the management of personal data. In these instances, Out Travel S.r.L. is obliged to comply to avoid a fine. 

Out Travel S.r.L., as "Owner" of the relative data management, informs that the data will be handled and used exclusively as per purposes highlighted in this communication. 

  5. **Right to access your personal data**  
Out Travel S.r.L. clients may request details of personal information held, to the Owner and/or data Manager, under art. 7 "Right to access personal data" of D. Lgs. 196/2003 n.196.  
List of people in charge of personal data handling. Compulsory information as per art.13 letter f Law Decree DLGS/196/2003: ALMATI S.r.L. Personnel.
  6. **Newsletter**  
We inform you that the newsletter service is carried out independently by ALPAL, so in the case of your newsletter subscription to WWW.OUTTRAVEL.IT the address that you supply will be used exclusively by our company for the transmission of messages containing our promotional and commercial offers. The ALPAL. is, therefore, also as owner of the processing and storage of your e-mail.
